rspb.org.uk 2015-12-26

# The RSPB: About our site: Privacy and cookies policy

Print page

  * Home >
  * About our site >
  * Privacy and cookies policy

This statement applies to:

  * The RSPB, registered charity in England and Wales 207076, in Scotland SC037654, The Lodge, Sandy, Bedfordshire SG19 2DL
  * RSPB Sales Limited, registered company number 2693778, The Lodge, Sandy, Bedfordshire SG19 2DL

The RSPB and RSPB Sales Limited are registered as data controllers with the Information Commissioner for the United Kingdom.

We are committed to protecting your privacy and security. Whenever you provide personal information, we will treat that information in accordance with this policy, current UK Data Protection legislation and Internet best practice.

You can use most of the features of this site without disclosing any personal information. A few optional features of this site, such as membership enrolment forms, ask you to provide some personal information (eg. name and address, e-mail address).

We will analyse information provided by you in order to determine which communications are most effective, and help us to reduce our administration cost and increase the funds available for conservation. If we wish to use your personal information for an additional purpose, we will always ask you to agree at the point of collection.

If you have already supplied us with personal information, you can change your instructions at any time by contacting Supporter Services on 01767 693680 or writing to Supporter Services, The RSPB, The Lodge, Sandy, Bedfordshire SG19 2DL.

### Uses of personal data

The RSPB and RSPB Sales Ltd will use your details for:

  * Administering your membership 
  * Communications about conservation and campaigns
  * Fundraising
  * Marketing purposes
  * Fulfilment of orders for goods and services
  * Administration of donations and legacies
  * Administering volunteer records
  * Customer satisfaction surveys
  * In-house research and analysis
  * The purpose of prevention and detection of crime
  * Informing you about products and services

We may share your details with trusted service providers in order to fulfil the above services.  Where this service is done on behalf of the RSPB this is done under contract and relevant security measures are taken.

### Disclosure of data

We will not sell your data to any third party; however, we may share with trusted service providers in order to fulfil the required services to you.

Where other companies are used to capture data or undertake fulfilment services on our behalf, these activities are carried out under contract in compliance with the Data Protection Act requirements.

The Privacy Policy will apply whenever you provide personal information, except as required by law, where the RSPB can pass on personal data without consent for example for the purpose to prevent and detect crime.

### Consent

By providing personal data you consent to its processing as described in this Privacy Policy. The first time you are asked to submit your personal details you will see the following notice:

We respect your privacy and will not sell your personal data to any third party.

The RSPB and RSPB Sales Ltd will use your details to tell you about our conservation and fundraising; to run your membership; to conduct analysis and to contact you for research purposes. If you do not wish to receive marketing information in the following ways, please tick the relevant box:

[ ] Mail [ ] Telephone [ ] E-mail [ ] Text

For further information on the full range of our activities and your privacy choices, please see our Privacy Policy or contact Supporter Services on tel: 01767 693680.

You will be indicating your consent to receiving marketing messages from us UNLESS you have indicated an objection to receiving such messages by ticking the appropriate box. You will continue to receive information of those products or services that are likely to be of interest to you, in accordance with the preferences that you indicated when you provided your personal data.

If at any point you would like to opt out of receiving communications, including marketing, from us or would like to change the channel of communication for example email or post that we use to contact you, please contact Supporter Services, RSPB, the Lodge, Sandy Bedfordshire SG19 2DL or telephone 01767 693680.

### Users aged under 18

If you are aged under 18, please ensure you obtain your parent/guardian's consent before sending any personal information to this website or the RSPB. Please note that the RSPB will not accept online donations or orders for goods or services from persons aged under 18 years.

We do have activities for under 18, our younger audience, prior to taking part in these please ensure you speak to your parent or guardian.

### Parents and guardians

We encourage you to be aware of the activities in which your children are participating in both offline and online, particularly with regard to third party websites. If your children voluntarily disclose information, this may encourage unsolicited messages. We suggest that you discourage your child from providing any information without your consent.

### Access to your own information

You can contact us anytime by letter or telephone to change or update your details.  You can obtain a copy of your record (this is known as subject access request), please note that we reserve the right to charge a fee of £10 for any such request.  

If you have any problems or queries about your data, please contact Supporter Services, RSPB, The Lodge, Sandy, Bedfordshire SG19 2DL or telephone 01767 693680.

### Cookies and tracking

A cookie is a piece of data about a website that is stored in your web browser. Cookies are often used to store choices about how you use the site to improve your user experience. The RSPB website makes use of cookies in this way, and also to help us get a feel for what it is you're all looking at. They are anonymous; they only give us information about the number of visitors to our site, so we don't know what you personally are looking at, more than someone has looked at what you've looked at.

Some bits of our site rely on cookies, but we'll tell you where and when. Most browsers will allow you to control how cookies are handled, whether they are accepted and how long they are stored for. All browsers do this differently, but if you're concerned about privacy and security then please have a look in the 'help' documentation for your particular browser.

We also make use of some simple image files provided by suppliers, such as DoubleClick and Google Analytics, to help measure the usage of our site, show relevant advertising and track the results of our advertising on third party websites. They are tiny and transparent, so they can't be seen, and won't make any noticeable difference to your experience, nor do they give away any personal data.

You may notice some third party cookies not related to RSPB when you visit a page, the RSPB does not control these cookies and we recommend you check the third party websites for more information.

The type of cookies used and their purpose is explained further:

  * Community Server cookies and authorization cookie are required for the provision of the community website and to provide security.
  * Personalisation module is required to provide the personalised service.
  * Google analytic cookies are used to collect information about how visitors, like yourself, use our website. This information is collected in an anonymous form and is used to inform us how the site can be improved.
  * Magento ecommerce, RSPB Images and affiliate future cookies are necessary as these enable you to make purchases, from areas such as the RSPB online shop, purchasing of memberships and images through the relevant websites.
  * Online advertising and network cookies are used to track when you have clicked on an advert, to see what pages of the website are used and this provides insight as to how improvements can be made. We also have relationships with carefully-selected advertising partners who may also set cookies during your visit to allow them to serve online advertising that we believe will be of interest to you based on information about your visit to this and other websites (this is called re-targeting). This information is anonymous and does not include personal data. For more information about this type of online behavioural advertising and about how to turn this feature off, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.co.uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.co.uk/).

A list of the main cookies the RSPB uses can be found [here](http://www.rspb.org.uk/help/cookies.aspx).

Further information about cookies including how to manage and delete them can be found at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Financial security

All RSPB forms which request credit card or bank details use the SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) protocol for encryption. Most web browsers (Microsoft Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Safari, Google Chrome etc) support SSL. The link between your web browser and the server is secure if your web browser displays a small padlock or key symbol somewhere in the frame, or the address bar shows a web address beginning https:// (rather than http://).

### Links to third party websites

The RSPB website contains hyperlinks to many other websites. This information is supplied in good faith, in case it is of interest, or use, to RSPB website users. The RSPB is not responsible for the content or functionality of any of these external websites – but please let us know if a link is not working (use the '[Contact us](http://www.rspb.org.uk/contactus/)' link which can be found at the top of every page). Visitors to the RSPB website should be aware of the following:

If an external website requests personal information from you (eg in connection with an order for goods or services), this information is supplied to, stored and used by the company concerned – it is not covered by the RSPB's Data Protection Notice. It is good practice to read the privacy policy of any website at which you are considering registering any personal information.

In purchasing goods or services from any of the companies to which the RSPB site links, you are forming a contract with the company(s) concerned (agreeing to their terms and conditions), not the RSPB.

### Notification of change of Privacy Policy

The RSPB reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Notice of any change will be posted on our website and will be deemed effective on publication. Your continued use of this website after changes are posted constitutes your acceptance of these Terms and Conditions.
